Lisa Mabley

Senior Full-Stack Software Engineer

lisamabley@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/lisamabley/ Website: lisamabley.github.io https://github.com/LisaMabley (612) 817-7516 Minneapolis, MN 55413

PROFILE

Engineering leader and technical problem solver with 8+ years of full stack software engineering experience, notably with *TypeScript*, *Node*, and *PostgreSQL*. Over 10 years of experience wearing many hats in small/early-stage startups. Tech generalist: nimble and quick to learn new frameworks. Exceptional collaboration, mentoring, teamwork, and communication skills. Passionate about mission-driven work to make the world a better place.

EXPERIENCE

Joyuus, Boston MA - Founding Engineer

SEPT 2023 - PRESENT

- Over a 4 month period, I evolved the product from a clickable prototype to a functional minimum viable product, and launched the application for clinical trial users. I set up analytics and tracking with *Amplitude* and *Pendo* to ensure clinical trial results are robust enough to provide actionable insights, along with persuasive impact numbers for potential investors. I also provided leadership on tool/stack recommendations, roadmap timing assessment, allocation of resources and feature prioritization.
 AWS, React, TypeScript, Node, PostgreSQL, Contentful, Clerk
- I collaborated with my team to develop our roadmap for phase two, and launched the
 public beta testing phase. I reinforced authentication security and laid the groundwork for
 enterprise client connections with autho. I added audio narration using AWS Polly
 Al-generated voices, as well as and CASL role-based acess control.
 AWS, React, TypeScript, Node, PostgreSQL, Contentful, Prisma

Cloudburst SBC, Minneapolis MN - Senior Full-Stack Software Developer

MAY 2018 - APRIL 2023

- I built and scaled a public-facing mobile app, corporate content management system, and REST API for a senior living company with thousands of users and dozens of properties around the country; Created Integrated an IoT platform with fleet-managed devices; Released mobile apps to the Google Play store and iOS App Store; Prototyped an Amazon Alexa skill; Imported data from external systems.
 - TypeScript, React, Angular, Node, PostgreSQL, Ionic, Capacitor, GCP, AWS
- I enhanced a million-dollar yard care application project by adding customer data import, estimation functionality and a subcontractor layer, reducing manual work.
 TypeScript, React, Supabase, Node, Next.js, GCP

- I established baseline data analytics and KPI levels for a rapidly-growing telehealth client, revealing and correcting gaps in data collection. I created an admin dashboard to track and visualize employee performance and care standards for a large volume of patients.
 PostgreSQL, Big Query, Google Data Studio, GCP
- I created a HIPAA-compliant logging system and client dashboard to track signup failures and abandons, allowing a healthcare client to optimize its account creation and health history input process, unlocking product improvements and onboarding insights.
 Sentry, Google Data Studio, GCP
- I scaled a training and regulatory compliance client's applications from 2,000 users to 44,000+ users; I optimized the REST API back-end service by streamlining queries and caching database results; I upgraded front-end app performance via table pagination, search, and sort; I released mobile apps to the Google Play and iOS app stores.
 TypeScript, Angular, Node, Firebase, PostgreSQL, Ionic, GCP

ITM TwentyFirst, Minneapolis MN - Full-Stack Software Engineer
JUNE 2016 - MAY 2018

- I built a public-facing web app and REST API service for new customers to log in and confirm/update contact information, saving the company significant costs by automating a time-consuming step of customer interaction. TypeScript, Angular, Node, MS SQL Server
- I synthesized large datasets and wrote complex queries, functions, and stored procedures
 to isolate the financial products with the highest value, and provide clients with actionable
 information. MS SQL Server

Martin Williams Advertising, Minneapolis MN - Digital Production Artist OCTOBER 2006 - SEPTEMBER 2013

EDUCATION

Prime Digital Academy, Minneapolis, MN - Full Stack Software Engineering Certificate Completed an 18-week immersive program in full-stack software engineering using JavaScript, Angular, Node.js, Express, and MySQL

Minneapolis College, Minneapolis, MN

Took semester courses in *Python*, *Java*, *iOS/Objective-C*, and *Android* development.

University of Minnesota – Twin Cities, Minneapolis, MN - Bachelor's Degree

Completed a liberal arts bachelor's degree program with a major in art. Transformed my car into an "artcar" as my senior project.

TOP SKILLS

- Languages: TypeScript, JavaScript, SQL, HTML/CSS, Java, Python
- Frameworks: Node.js, React.js, Express, Angular
- Databases: PostgreSQL, Cloud Firestore, MySQL, SQL Server
- Data Tools: Google Data Studio, Big Query
- Cloud Platforms: GCP, AWS, Firebase, Supabase, Heroku
- Mobile Tools: Ionic, Cordova, Capacitor
- Testing Tools: Playwright, Mocha, Jest, Jasmine
- ORM: Prisma, TypeORM
- **CI/CD:** GitHub Actions
- **Performance Monitoring:** Sentry
- Dev Tools: GitHub, BitBucket, Jira, Docker, npm, Yarn, Homebrew, Asana, Notion
- Creative: Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign)
- Methodologies: Agile

MENTORING

- Prime Digital Academy: employed as full stack engineering teaching assistant, 2023
- Code Switch civic hackathons: volunteer for annual single-day events, 2018-2019
- Hack the Gap hackathons: volunteer for annual single-day events for female-identified and nonbinary adults, 2018-2019 website mentor profile
- Prime Digital Academy: volunteer mentor for 20-week full-stack engineering bootcamp programs for adults, 2017-2018
- **Technovation Challenge:** volunteer teaching assistant for 3-month program to educate junior high and high school girls about tech entrepreneurship, 2017
- CoderDojo Twin Cities: volunteer teaching assistant for monthly single-day events to introduce elementary school students to coding, 2015
- Big Brothers Big Sisters Twin Cities: 8+ year relationship, starting in 2000 news article